dbqschools.org 2014-12-14

# Privacy Statement

**Dubuque Community Schools' Privacy Statement**

**_Most recent update October 23, 2008_**

he Dubuque Community School District recognizes and respects your need for privacy and security as you visit our site. When you visit our site to view any pages, read district information, or use our on-line calendar and other features, you do so without telling us who you are and without revealing any personal information. While we do not collect identifying information about visitors to our site, we do use standard software to collect information for the strict purpose of tracking activity on our site. This allows us to better understand how many people use our site and which pages and features are most popular. The only information we normally collect and store is:

  * The name of your Internet service provider. 
  * The web site that referred you to us (if any). 
  * The date and time the pages were accessed. 
  * The page or pages you requested. 

There are instances where you may elect to provide us with personal information. If you fill out one of our feedback or request forms or send us email, you are transmitting the information that appears to you in the form or the message. This will typically include information like your name, mailing address, email address, the kind of request you are making, and any other information necessary to fulfill your request. You never transmit personally identifying information that you do not enter yourself. And this is always your option; this information cannot be collected unless you specifically elect to send it to us. This information is used internally only for the purpose of fulfilling the request or for contacting you directly and is not given or sold to any other organization.

The Dubuque Community School District makes every attempt to maintain privacy and information safeguards in compliance with the Family Educational Rights Privacy Act (FERPA). The rights of students and parents to privacy are guaranteed by FERPA, and the district actively respects that right. 

We reserve the right to change our privacy policy. A revised policy statement will only apply to data collected subsequent to its effective date. Any revisions will be posted at least 30 days prior to its effective date.

We hope you find our website useful and informative. We are always willing to answer questions and receive suggestions. If you have either, please e-mail the Webmaster at [**golsen@dubuque.k12.ia.us**](mailto:golsen@dubuque.k12.ia.us). Thank you. 

| 

_"While we do not collect identifying information about visitors to our site, we do use standard software to collect information for the strict purpose of tracking activity on our site."_

* * *

_**Download our Acceptable Use Policy Document and our Parental Permission forms:**_

We receive many requests from other school districts as well as parents on how we protect the privacy of our students and their families in the event parents do not want photos of their children to appear on the Web site or in any other media form from videos to published documents. At the beginning of the year, we provide families with a **Dubuque Community School District Acceptable Use Policy and Related Information** sheet along with a **Parental Release Form** that allows parents to grant or withhold permission to feature their child in any media opportunity that may come along during the coming year. The teachers and principals quickly learn who can be photographed and who cannot. It saves us a lot of time and hassles in the process of producing videos and taking photographs in our district. Of course we double check permissions with teachers on every project before its release. By clicking on the button above or link below, you can download the **Acceptable Use Policy (Adobe Acrobat)** or the **Parental Release Form (Adobe Acrobat)**.

| 

© 2000, 2003, 2004, 2005, 2006 Dubuque Community Schools All Rights Reserved. No portion of this Web site can be reproduced without expressed permission of the Dubuque Community School District. Contact Dubuque Community Schools, **[Office of Public Affairs](mailto:golsen@dubuque.k12.ia.us)** , 2300 Chaney Road, Dubuque, IA 52001. View our  **Privacy Statement**. Phone: 563-552-3032.

_If you are an employee of the Dubuque Community School Distrct, The Hub is for you. You need your building name  
and password to gain access. Ask your school secretary or media specialist for that information. _
